Guide to the Robert Garcia papers, 1988-1993
Garcia, Robert papers, 1988-1993
- Series VII. Graphic Material
  - Picture: "Greta Garbo in Susan Lenox Her Fall and Rise, 5 (Box 9)
  - Fold out poster/flyer for the 4th Annual Lesbian and Gay New York Film Festival, Sept. 1990, 6 (Box 9)
  - Broadside for the Safe Drugs Rally, NYC, May, n.y., 7 (Box 9)
  - Bag with advertisement for Tom Duane, City Council of NYC, 8 (Box 9)
  - MEC Magazine, Jan. 1987, 9 (Box 9)
  - Flyer for Armed Forces Day Salute & GVA Freedom Awards Benefit at Tracks, NYC, May 1988, 10 (Box 9)
  - Flyer for an ACT UP benefit concert, NYC, May, 1988, 11 (Box 9)
  - "25% Test Positive" poster, regarding prisoners with AIDS, 12 (Box 9)
  - NY Peace Network Calendar, #62, Feb., 1989, 13 (Box 9)
  - "Deadlier than the Virus", ripped off piece of a poster, 14 (Box 9)
  - Poster for If Men Could Talk, The Stories They Could Tell performance, NYC, 15 (Box 9)
  - NYC Lesbian & Gay Pride History month poster, June 1989, 16 (Box 9)
  - NYC Lesbian & Gay Pride History month poster, June 1990, 17 (Box 9)
  - NYC Lesbian & Gay Pride History month poster, June 1988, 18 (Box 9)
  - World AIDS Day 1990 poster, Dec. 1990, 19 (Box 9)
  - Broadside for A Man Cannot Jump Over His Own Shadow performance, NYC, Jan., n.y., 20 (Box 9)
  - Poster, "Video for Advocacy, Resistance, & Self-Empowerment", advertising a movie series, NYC, Apr. 1988, 21 (Box 9)
  - Page from a newspaper advertising a performance of We Keep Our Victims Ready by Karen Finley, NYC, 1990, 22 (Box 9)
  - Publication, Le Manifeste de Montreal, by AIDS Action NOW! Toronto and ACT UP NY, 1989, 23 (Box 9)
  - "ACTUP Fight Back Fight AIDS" advertising poster, NYC, 24 (Box 9)
  - 2 large sheets of notes on ACT UP and community involvement, 25 (Box 9)
  - "Remember Them And Be Reminded" AIDS Quilt unfolding advertisement flyer, NYC, June, n.y., 26 (Box 9)
    One in English, one in Spanish
  - Two posters (?) of an eye, 27 (Box 9)
  - "State Stiffs City On AIDS Care Funds & Drug Treatment" poster, 28 (Box 9)
  - Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade information booklet, 1989, 29 (Box 9)
  - "You Can Do It All Just Do It Safer" poster, one side in English one in Spanish, 30 (Box 9)
  - "John Blair Opening Night at Roxy" poster, June 1991, 31 (Box 9)
  - "Homo Hate", boycotting The Gap broadside, 32 (Box 9)
  - "Democracy: Group Material" exhibition poster, NYC, 33 (Box 9)
  - Poster advertisement/invitation for The Men's Room Bar, NYC, June 1991, 34 (Box 9)
  - "Boycott White Powder Bring Back Herb!" broadside for Safe Drugs Rally, NYC, 35 (Box 9)
  - Poster/artwork (?) of a naked man, with letters "E A", 36 (Box 9)
  - ACT-UP NYC performance benefit broadside, 37 (Box 9)
  - Malibu Men calendar, 1988, 38 (Box 9)
  - Photocopies of articles, flyers, press conferences, etc. related to the Apollo Theatre, NYC, 1990, 39 (Box 9)
  - "Enjoy AZT" broadside, 40 (Box 9)
  - Photocopies of artwork, 41 (Box 9)
  - "Serial Killer" with a picture of George Bush broadside, 42 (Box 9)
  - Poster for "The Center Show" commissioned by the NYC Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center, 1989, 43 (Box 9)
  - "Outmusic: The Lesbian & Gay Music Festival" poster, June 1991, 44 (Box 9)
  - Large "Universal Declaration of Human Rights" by the UN poster, 1985, 45 (Box 9)
  - "Read This O Queers" broadside/manifesto, published anonymously by queers, 46 (Box 9)
  - Copies of articles related to Alzheimers Disease, from The Wall Street Journal, 4/30/1991, 47 (Box 9)
  - Copy of "Read My Lips" broadside, with dates and descriptions of events by ACT UP NYC, Apr.-May, n.y., 48 (Box 9)
  - Copy of "Sexism Rears Its Unprotected Head" poster, 1988, 49 (Box 9)
  - "Freedom Can Seem Like A Revolutionary Idea" small flyer, 50 (Box 9)
  - "Because..." lesbian & gay civil rights movement poster, 1991, 50 (Box 9)
  - NYC Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project poster, 51 (Box 9)
    With 24 hour crime victim's hotline number. One in English, one in Spanish.
  - Posters, broadsides, photographs, etc. (Map-case Folder 1)
- Series VIII. Video Material
  - Robert Garcia Memorial, V-110; [VHS videotape-use copy]
  - Robert Garcia Memorial, V-110; [VHS videotape-preservation copy]
  - Robert Garcia Memorial, DVD-50; [DVD-preservation copy]
  - Our Family: The Garcias, V-111; [VHS videotape]
  - Our Family: The Garcias, V-111 c.2; [Beta Videotape] (Box 15)
  - Our Family: The Garcias, DVD-455; [Use copy of V-111] (Box 17)
  - Robert Garcia 1/18/89 copyright 1989 Jim Hubbard, V-112; [VHS videotape]
  - Robert Garcia 1/18/89 copyright 1989 Jim Hubbard, V-112 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Robert Garcia 1/18/89 copyright 1989 Jim Hubbard, DVD-456; [Use copy of V-112] (Box 17)
  - Robert Garcia and Karen Ramspacher at John Jay College Spring 1991, V-113; [VHS videotape-use copy]
  - Robert Garcia and Karen Ramspacher at John Jay College Spring 1991, V-113 c.2; [VHS videotape-preservation copy]
  - Robert Garcia and Karen Ramspacher at John Jay College Spring 1991, DVD-51; [DVD-preservation copy]
  - Phil Donahue with ACT UP--Robert 2/13/90, V-114; [VHS videotape]
  - Phil Donahue with ACT UP--Robert 2/13/90, V-114 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Phil Donahue with ACT UP--Robert 2/13/90, DVD-457; [Use copy of V-114] (Box 17)
  - Turning Anger Into Action: Robert on the Panel, V-115; [VHS videotape]
  - Turning Anger Into Action: Robert on the Panel, V-115 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Turning Anger Into Action: Robert on the Panel, DVD-458; [Use copy of V-115] (Box 17)
  - Activist History in SF/ Zonal Music Video/ Black Filmmakers--Phil Donohue, V-116; [VHS videotape]
  - Activist History in SF/ Zonal Music Video/ Black Filmmakers--Phil Donohue, V-116 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Activist History in SF/ Zonal Music Video/ Black Filmmakers--Phil Donohue, DVD-459; [Use copy of V-116] (Box 17)
  - Writers Responsibilities, V-117; [VHS videotape]
  - Writers Responsibilities, V-117 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Writers Responsibilities, DVD-460; [Use copy of V-117] (Box 17)
  - United Colors/ Museum, V-118; [VHS videotape]
  - United Colors/ Museum, V-118 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - United Colors/ Museum, DVD-461; [Use copy of V-118] (Box 17)
  - Robert Garcia--Town Meeting on PBS [June 1990], V-119; [VHS videotape]
  - Robert Garcia--Town Meeting on PBS [June 1990], V-119 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Robert Garcia--Town Meeting on PBS [June 1990], DVD-462; [Use copy of V-119] (Box 17)
  - Robert Garcia Town Meeting, V-120; [VHS videotape]
  - Robert Garcia Town Meeting, V-120 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Robert Garcia Town Meeting, DVD-463; [Use copy of V-120] (Box 17)
  - Leadership Roundtable Tape 1, V-121; [VHS videotape]
  - Leadership Roundtable Tape 1, V-121; [VHS videotape]
  - Leadership Roundtable Tape 1, V-121 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Leadership Roundtable Tape 1, DVD-464; [Use copy of V-121] (Box 17)
  - Leadership Roundtable Tape 2, V-122; [VHS videotape]
  - Leadership Roundtable Tape 2, V-122 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 15)
  - Leadership Roundtable Tape 2, DVD-465; [Use copy of V-122] (Box 17)
  - Leadership Institute Tape 1, V-123; [VHS videotape]
  - Leadership Institute Tape 1, V-123 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 16)
  - Leadership Institute Tape 1, DVD-466; [Use copy of V-123] (Box 17)
  - "HOUSE" Safe Sex/ Fundraising, V-124; GHMC Assistant Coordinator for People of Color Prevention Programs talking at a conference about ways he's working to reach youth. He discovered a good place to reach these youth is through their Houses, social networks of Black and Hispanic kids, originating out of drag balls. He describes attending balls, passing out condoms, coming up with a voguing safe sex message. Also, conference session on fundraising.; [VHS videotape]
  - "HOUSE" Safe Sex/ Fundraising, V-124 c.2; GHMC Assistant Coordinator for People of Color Prevention Programs talking at a conference about ways he's working to reach youth. He discovered a good place to reach these youth is through their Houses, social networks of Black and Hispanic kids, originating out of drag balls. He describes attending balls, passing out condoms, coming up with a voguing safe sex message. Also, conference session on fundraising.; [Beta videotape] (Box 16)
  - "HOUSE" Safe Sex/ Fundraising, DVD-467; GHMC Assistant Coordinator for People of Color Prevention Programs talking at a conference about ways he's working to reach youth. He discovered a good place to reach these youth is through their Houses, social networks of Black and Hispanic kids, originating out of drag balls. He describes attending balls, passing out condoms, coming up with a voguing safe sex message. Also, conference session on fundraising.; [Use copy of V-124] (Box 17)
  - End of Fundraising/ Brother to Brother Reading/Plenary Wilson Speech, V-125; [VHS videotape]
  - End of Fundraising/ Brother to Brother Reading/Plenary Wilson Speech, V-125 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 16)
  - End of Fundraising/ Brother to Brother Reading/Plenary Wilson Speech, DVD-468; [Use copy of V-125] (Box 17)
  - End of Fundraising/ Brother to Brother Reading/Plenary Wilson Speech, V-126; [VHS videotape]
  - Self Publishing, V-127; Interviews with a group of Black male writers about getting published. Rory (?) Buchanan, a single parent, poet, fiction writer from Brooklyn; Alan Miller, a poet and high school teacher from Oakland; Steven Corbin, a novelist, short fiction writer, essayist and teacher from New York City, author of No Easy Place to Be and Fragments That Remain; John (?) Gwen (?), writer from San Diego; and Mark Hale, staff writer for BLK and literary coordinator for DIVA, a multicultural lesbian, gay arts group in Los Angeles.; [VHS videotape]
  - Self Publishing, V-127 c.2; Interviews with a group of Black male writers about getting published. Rory (?) Buchanan, a single parent, poet, fiction writer from Brooklyn; Alan Miller, a poet and high school teacher from Oakland; Steven Corbin, a novelist, short fiction writer, essayist and teacher from New York City, author of No Easy Place to Be and Fragments That Remain; John (?) Gwen (?), writer from San Diego; and Mark Hale, staff writer for BLK and literary coordinator for DIVA, a multicultural lesbian, gay arts group in Los Angeles.; [Beta videotape] (Box 16)
  - Self Publishing, DVD-469; Interviews with a group of Black male writers about getting published. Rory (?) Buchanan, a single parent, poet, fiction writer from Brooklyn; Alan Miller, a poet and high school teacher from Oakland; Steven Corbin, a novelist, short fiction writer, essayist and teacher from New York City, author of No Easy Place to Be and Fragments That Remain; John (?) Gwen (?), writer from San Diego; and Mark Hale, staff writer for BLK and literary coordinator for DIVA, a multicultural lesbian, gay arts group in Los Angeles.; [Use copy of V-127] (Box 17)
  - End of Self Publishing/ Raw Eroticism, V-128; [VHS videotape]
  - End of Self Publishing/ Raw Eroticism, V-128 c.2; [Beta videotape] (Box 16)
  - End of Self Publishing/ Raw Eroticism, DVD-470; [Use copy of V-128] (Box 17)
  - House of Color/ Hill/ When He Has AIDS, V-129; Video about how the sexuality of people of color is fetishized and marginalized, including interviews with lesbian/gay/bisexual Asians, Native Americans, and other groups about how they found community. An address by Dr, Marjorie Hill, Mayor Koch's liaison to the lesbian/bisexual/gay community. Unidentified man speaking at a conference talking about how he dealt with his lover having AIDS and dying.; [VHS videotape]
  - House of Color/ Hill/ When He Has AIDS, V-129 c.2; Video about how the sexuality of people of color is fetishized and marginalized, including interviews with lesbian/gay/bisexual Asians, Native Americans, and other groups about how they found community. An address by Dr, Marjorie Hill, Mayor Koch's liaison to the lesbian/bisexual/gay community. Unidentified man speaking at a conference talking about how he dealt with his lover having AIDS and dying.; [Beta videotape] (Box 16)
  - House of Color/ Hill/ When He Has AIDS, DVD-471; Video about how the sexuality of people of color is fetishized and marginalized, including interviews with lesbian/gay/bisexual Asians, Native Americans, and other groups about how they found community. An address by Dr, Marjorie Hill, Mayor Koch's liaison to the lesbian/bisexual/gay community. Unidentified man speaking at a conference talking about how he dealt with his lover having AIDS and dying.; [Use copy of V-129] (Box 17)
  - Speak for Yourself--A Videotape by Jim Hubbard: David France; Alan Klein; Karl Soehnlein; Maxine Wolfe; Sarah Schulman; Robert Garcia; Gregg Bordowitz, V-130; Robert's section begins circa 23 minutes into film. He declares that being half-Navajo, half-Mexican, and gay are the three things that identify who he is. He talks about losing his Hispanic and Navajo heritage because his parents wanted to assimilate. The only thing he hasn't lost is his gay identity, because he discovered that himself. He said he realized that the AIDS crisis is destroying this heritage.; [VHS videotape]
  - Speak for Yourself--A Videotape by Jim Hubbard: David France; Alan Klein; Karl Soehnlein; Maxine Wolfe; Sarah Schulman; Robert Garcia; Gregg Bordowitz, V-130 c.2; Robert's section begins circa 23 minutes into film. He declares that being half-Navajo, half-Mexican, and gay are the three things that identify who he is. He talks about losing his Hispanic and Navajo heritage because his parents wanted to assimilate. The only thing he hasn't lost is his gay identity, because he discovered that himself. He said he realized that the AIDS crisis is destroying this heritage.; [Beta videotape] (Box 16)
  - Speak for Yourself--A Videotape by Jim Hubbard: David France; Alan Klein; Karl Soehnlein; Maxine Wolfe; Sarah Schulman; Robert Garcia; Gregg Bordowitz, DVD-472; Robert's section begins circa 23 minutes into film. He declares that being half-Navajo, half-Mexican, and gay are the three things that identify who he is. He talks about losing his Hispanic and Navajo heritage because his parents wanted to assimilate. The only thing he hasn't lost is his gay identity, because he discovered that himself. He said he realized that the AIDS crisis is destroying this heritage.; [Use copy of V-130] (Box 17)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
List Of Periodicals Removed From Robert Garcia Collection, And Placed In The Human Sexuality Collection Periodicals:
PWA (People with AIDS) Newsline (8 folders)
Body Positive (7 folders)
Black/Out
A Different Light Review
SIDA Hora
ATR (AIDS Treatment Registry) (2 folders)
PI Perspective (2 folders)
AIDSINFO Digest
AIDS/HIV Experimental Treatment Directory
STOP THE VIOLENCE
HOLY TIT CLAMPS
ALTER EGO
Reverberate
HOMOture
PANSY BEAT
TED
ONE
Radical America (2 folders)
B and G
My Comrade
Genre
San Francisco Sentinel
Gay Community News
Sappho's Isle
The ABC No Rio Rag
MEC
VIVA!
BLK (3 folders)
SOUP
VISIBILITIES
GAIPIED
Reproductive Rights Newsletter
ADVOCATE (2 folders)
APLA UPDATE
News Jersey
OUTCRY
NJ ACT UP
BEING ALIVE
Treatment Issues
AIDS Treatment News
GLAAD Bulletin
Single Issues
Breakthrough
Our World
Science Fiction Chronicle
Streetwize Comics
Pink Triangle
Image
Pussy Grazer (zine)
Whispering Campaign (zine)
Brains (zine)
Michael's Thing (zine)
BIMBOX (zine)
The Independent
GS (Gay Scotland)
Die Heisse Nummer (The Hot Number) - German periodical
Mediafile
Piss Elegant (zine)
Caribbean Heat
!AHA!
Factsheet Fire
EDGE
The Children's Voice
LA Weekly
Frontiers
GAWK
DPN (Diseased Pariah News)
The Pyramid Periodical
NYQ
SIN BROS.
Gayellow Pages
Straight to Hell
Christopher Street
QW
James White Review
The Newsletter
Arizona Community Echo
GAPS (The Gay [Men's] Amateur Press Society)
Project X
Optimist
Wisconsin Light
Reality Check
Fertile La Toyah
DEAN
J.D.'s
Surviving and Thriving With AIDS: Hints for the Newly Diagnosed
Lesbian Herstory Archives
Lesbian Contradiction
[Swish]
[Ashtray]
List Of Books Removed From Robert Garcia's Collection:
Between The Lines, 1987
editors: C. Chung, A. Kim, A. K. Lemeshewsky
Homosexual Counseling Journal, July 1974, April 1976
editor: Ralph Blair
...And Justice for All
trustee: Michael M. Berlin
AIDS, Civil Rights and the Public Health: America's Leaders Speak Out, 1988
published by NGRA (National Gay Rights Advocates)
Drawing on the Gay Experience, 1987
Gerard P. Donelan
Donelan's Back, 1988
Gerard P. Donelan
Heal Your Body, 1976
Louise L. Hay
Living with Aids, 1987
Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc.
The Politics of AIDS, 1986
Nancy Krieger, Rose Appleman
Socialist Review (SR) October - December 1988
Executive editor: Ron Silliman
The Evergreen Chronicles, Winter 1987
editors: Don Markus Matsen, Barrie Jean Borich, Doug Federhart, Lisa Albrecht
Bowers vs. Hardwick: The Supreme Court and Sodomy, 1986
Jim Peron
The Combahee River Collective Statement: Black Feminist Organizing Seventies and Eighties, 1986
editor: Barbara Smith
STRIP AIDS(comic book)
Gay Freedom 1970 editors of QQ
Other Countries: Black Gay Voices
No Title
Theo Lipfert